we're gonna talk about to talk on
tablets yeah
Oh NHS sure
what is in each that's a good start so
I guess my first translation my first
word would be not permanent but then
that means lots of qualification
so something that's not permanent is
of the nature to change because
something which is permanent doesn't
change
it's such an inconceivable of something
being well I think people can yeah
people can think okay this is they can
assume yeah but if you have to stop and
think about can you give example or
something it's not subject to change
change well no but I mean so so for
instance people might say oh
impermanence means everything's changing
mmm that doesn't change yes for them yeah
that doesn't change yes for them yeah
which tie they're not seeing
impermanence yeah but
but
either but and no I think so I think I
would he said his and so what is
unachievable so it could meet a
Nietzsche would be the way I see it
would be so this having the nature of
change so so so the Buddhist says things
like so what is masa feeling perception
of the aggregates ER in your body
whatever is that nature or any chance so
so is it permanent as in they don't
change or are they of the nature to
change so the problem with why I'm
saying we've already talked about this
is that then you have to be very care
about what we mean by change oh yeah
but there's a problem before that as
well which is it's not things are
subject to change that's not the
question that would ask us know it
refers to the cicadas sarsen car isn't
permanent our sin Cara's subjected to change I
our sin Cara's subjected to change I
thought which determines the things yeah
things things that you take it to be
yours I think the you are so in order
then to arrive at the level were an itch
applause you need to reverse the order
and you need to follow the right order
so if if the Buddhist question or
statement sabes and Kara Nietzsche not
saw the Dhamma Nietzsche Salveson Karan
each a solution kara dukkha yeah
sabudana anata so if a starting point of
view to Gina is sabudana oughtta all
things are meaning and myself or for
myself I might not go around saying I
own everything but I could own things if
they come along
want to own them so you imply a
possibility of ownership which is a
possibility which has implicit a
possibility of pleasure satisfaction
everlasting permanence or whatever else
you want translated so now with debts
your starting attitude that's a starting
attitude of somebody who wants to
practice you can now understand on each
other on this like intellectual level
because you don't know where their level
is correctly so you can you can
certainly collect information about it
through reading sutras and so on but in
order to understand a Nietzsche you only
can be understood on the level of
Sankara not on the level of $40 that you
regard is yours so how do you then
arrive at the level of San Carlos
because if you just attend to it oh this
isn't permanent
that's another dumber yeah so sin Cara's
I how do we describe him before I
thought I was about meditation yeah yeah
right yeah we did say we're talking
about that which determines your sense
of self yeah so the necessary basis for
yourself the way you know yourself so
for the necessary basis for your sense
of self necessary basis for your
ownership for your identity
necessary basis for your actions for
your choices for your management
techniques necessary basis for practice
as well I've seen correctly now that 2d
permanence is so unless you're seeing
impermanence on that but indirectly on
the necessary basis for this which I am
attending to yeah
you're not seeing impermanence you're
just sort of pasting it over as a kind
of attitude
they will then cancel and deny
everything and by doing so also deny any
problem which you might have so
everything is impermanent everything
will come to pass thus doesn't matter
that I suffer right now well it matters
otherwise you wouldn't be going around
saying everything shall pass why are you
saying that if nothing bothers you to
begin with why do you care whether it
passed or not because you want because
you go away means you're not seeing
impermanence because you're looking at
you're looking at the level of things
and diamonds and observable things you
can attend and so on that's where you
expect to see impermanence can only be
discerned peripherally on the level of
the basis of things that make this
possible so if I'm looking at things now hearing
so if I'm looking at things now hearing
things now I like them I dislike them I
want more of this I don't want any of
this what is impermanence in regard to
their experience what where are the San
Carlos in regard to that experience like
sort of experience as a whole was that
this in relation to what I'm looking
hearing seeing anything the periphery
they kind of like they they so they're
indirect to my direction of attention
yeah but how would you then describe
them those endearing things what what
would be the unifying basis feeling
feeling ok yeah so the present Indians
feeling then you were not creator of
them it's already can order DBA Sankara
yeah depending whether you are acting
out of that feeling towards projective
things and so on I guess if it's
improper that's what feeling is that
yes that what's another thing that can
they also serve as a recognition of the
Lois and Carson sense of self
well no spending more can you see here
taste touch aren't you an account of it
agree on the conduit think about it if
your body is not there alive on its own
beforehand and that's so now we see for
okay so my body's here now how would you
look in again what you're seeing is your
sight what you're hearing is you're
basically your ears which means that's
not now that body because of which I can
see here taste touch you failing to see
that is you maintaining the attitude
that I can see itself yes can hear
itself and that is inconceivable even to
Petrosian if he stops and thinks about
even they fight the existentialist
philosophers neva
so Sankara then that is of the nature to
change isn't that level which you cannot
directly attend to you cannot observe
impermanence look in permanent
impermanent because that means it's out
there totally projected
well it allows you to not take it
personally if you understand
impermanence on the right level you
cannot not be affected by it on the
emotional level
that's where Samson Carta and Nietzsche
sabes Ankara Duke so all of the
determinations are pleasant because of
that not sometimes ladies sometimes are
that sometimes they could be pleasant
something no always all of them are
pleasant because always all of them
remain subjected to that nature of
abrupt change basically you have been
they've been thrust upon you like this
you've been subjected to you busy you're
always secondary to them you're always
contained within so if you look for
impermanence in things you can see hear
taste smell taste touch and so on
you're not gonna find it and that's
exactly how people then fall into view
oh yeah look the modern science says
that everything is constantly changing
that's what the Buddha mandala so does
the science make yourself honor there's
a science freedom sensuality and
suffering no not even close
I'm on yet here you are holding the view
then you understood impermanence that
the Buddha was teaching and what I want
is about it talk so much about
mindfulness is very much at the pottery
yeah exactly because that's the way to
deceive peripherally where you can
discern their nature because if you
attend to it directly something else the
term is what you're attending is that's
hard tension works in order for you to
attend something needs to be given as
that possibility
and an itch is on the level of the
possibilities the level of the nature
subjected to and so on so would you save
us the only someone a cigar is
recognition of the peripheral in regard
to my direct attention what I'm looking
at and now I'm discerning other things
without needing to move and look at them
directly because then there would be an
actual and something else is peripheral
yeah so it's ten at ten
to the kind of origin from which these
things whatever tending discerning
discerning the origin attending yes
there would be attention to itself yeah
yeah are you seeing itself instead of
recognize discerning what what what that
the sort of origin from which whatever
it is I'm attending to is what and the
origin meaning the necessary basis that
still has to be there like would you be
able to continue seeing getting elated
and kind of your sights depressed on
account of your sites in different
account of your sights if your eyes are
stone of their enduring here would that
be even conceivable helps they go so now
Valen seeing while I'm looking at these
things I have the knowledge that all of
this actually is present because my eyes
are still there and all the
possibilities allowed to engage on in on
account of my sights would be because
these eyes are still there and that's
when impermanence is on the level of
that knowledge of these eyes are still
there is a necessary basis for any
movement towards them against them both
neither whichever way I want I don't
want is because the eyes are still there
yeah that's it can you conceive can you
even imagine to be in control of the eye
organ in a sense of to prevent it from
being subjected to accidents for example
like you can you can protect but only
the extent of hope that it will work you
can ever imagine for sure and feel that
100% safety even even like you know the
level of control that you might feel
like I can close my eyes now but it
might not work or something like they
might stop working internally yes might
give us something my head then you lose
your sight oh your heart my stuff yeah
will your eyes be able to remain if the
rest of the world is a unity gets
discarded no yeah so not ignoring that
then yeah or rather
ignoring that is how you then failed to
see where that impermanence is yeah and
even when you come to practice Buddhism
you're then sort of I permanently
permanent but none of that undermines my
sense of self
yeah but impermanence on each of the way
they would have described it together
will be felt as dukkha and they will
automatically have to undermine your
sense of oughtta so so that so the thing
about these Sun colors is that they
their very nature is to change but that
change is like this sort of like abrupt
change yeah well let's let's let's talk
on the base of an example right here
right now so this entire conversation
from your point of view he is fully
enclosed within the necessary enduring
presence of your living body okay yeah
if you start dying right right away now
that's it conversation cannot possibly
remain yeah your thoughts about it
cannot remain well you were about to say
well you said none of that can you make
because the necessary basis is removed
so what is that necessary base is
subjective how would you describe its
characteristics sigh change but let's
just say bit more like so it's so it's
it's like I'm you I'm sure no that's
thing I wanted to say I've been
basically I've been subjected to the
fact that of this body like I can only
kind of discern it as already enduring
hmm on its own given to you gives or
sees me enjoy it on its own it's kind of
my recognition of it is secondary to
that think be mad and it's exactly that
the sense that things are for me given
to me yeah I can literally wake up in
this world and things are they're
accessible so to speak that's why we
assumed it to be
yeah that's why you need to go against
that grain and start questioning that
which is given to you what are the
properties of having something given to
you that it could be taken away it can
be taken away that you do not create it
yeah did you didn't did not have seen it's
did you didn't did not have seen it's
making it all I can do is kind of borrow
it use it yeah you make you something
yeah but like just like as the fact that
it
it's a rising is kind of abrupt in the
sense that I kind of well you were
presented with it yeah that's it so it
can also be yes it's yeah its nature
remains allow this outside of your
control out of sight outside of it like
the scope why because you haven't
created it that's the main thing and and
see if there would be clear if people
who maintain that clarity on that level
in regard to directions they will be
much less ignorance much less passion
much less saying to undo but see that
you were given you borrow basically you
found this there you couldn't see any
other owner so you assume yourself to be
an owner of it that's it and the only
reason you're still able to maintain
that sense of ownership is because you
don't well long enough sufficient enough
on the nature of that which is necessary
for your ownership but can you say I am
the owner master controller of my
properties if you have no properties if
all of your possessions were taken away
exactly so the only way then to maintain
the notion I am my own I am myself and
so on is to then maintain that
possessions as yours and the only way
you'll be able to maintain that is
because you don't keep thinking how they
actually are possessions so I am such as
such because of things I own because of
that they did this I did that I were
more of this I don't more of that so
only the possessions determine you as
such and the Buddha said himself is a
similarly king he's if he doesn't have
Kings possessions he wouldn't be being
the king so you're taking possession
things is sort of secondary to those
things already being there exactly
around the coffins it exactly so and you
will miss that themself is dependent
it's like fully enclosed within and full
and artfully yeah this thing which I
have don't see how a gratuitous then the
sense of ownership is whereby you know
that you didn't create these things your
possessions you only possess them
because they were given as possessive
old so to speak yet that somehow led you
to maintain a view a belief that you are
master controller who comes first who is
in charge of all of this yet there would
be none of this nor me master controller
if there are no things that I can
exercise my control over it what is the
nature of those things you can exercise
your control over that of the next
change they don't control the whole
thing they're actually completely
inaccessible to you again you cannot
conceive inside of them because you are
within them so to speak so you can't
conceive outside of them yeah any
relationship you have it's going to be
in the relationship of the level of them
being given to you so your body you can
talk you can move you can drink water
you can look you so you can use your
senses yeah because you're fully
enclosed within them yeah
and while you using these senses in the
careless manner you maintain the notion
that you are the owner user of these
senses they are mine
I'm not because senses are there before
and senses are there because I am and
that's a completely gratuitous
perversion of the right order you are
because you keep taking things to be
mine and you can only take things to my
mind when you don't see those
determinations as impermanent
so you are because you take
determinations to be mine
and you take them to be mine because
they're not felt unpleasant and they're
not fell unpleasantly because you don't
see them and subjected to change or
rather you ignore yes the fact that they
always remain subjected to change and
that is inconceivable for you to control
or have say in thus you gonna share the
same nature of the and what they are
subjected to so again it's like
see no seeing the danger not same danger
in the things the you appropriate
exactly appropriation so if you want to
start contemplating impermanence you
can't do it look that door is
impermanent that cup is impermanent
first you to find your sense of
ownership as in take something that is
dear to you yeah something that if it
were taken away you will not necessarily
remain emotionally indifferent yeah and
then work through that basis to undo
that appropriation don't just take
things you don't care about find things
you care about and then start applying
the same attitude of I don't care about
this like to the point of I'm
indifferent emotional in regard to this
because I know it cannot be mine even if
I want it to be mine cuz I don't like
like that's fine my feeling would be
this feeling is something that's it's
it's a difference it was yeah yeah
that's right if it's if it's felt
pleasantly it's because you haven't seen
it
subjected to change yeah so if you start
seeing it as all this is subject to
change as in it's not changing yeah yeah
it's subject to change means it could
change and I cannot possibly consider
Minzy will change you kind of already
know that that's that's it's that's on
it that's its nature that's inside yeah
what it is to be this yes the only way
to deal with it is to notice any way to
deal with it for petitions do you know
it to ignore the fact that the only way
to deal with the unpleasantness of
things being subjected to change yeah
history is to ignore it
hence ignorance is that's why it's too
much for the metal
distraction delusion and so on it's an
active choice you make I choose to look
away from this I choose to ignore this
because not ignoring it undermines my
whole being so if your body right here
right now this objective is subject to a
to an abrupt change yeah doesn't matter
whether it's changing a little bit of
much on different levels that you can
observe what matters is that it's in its
nature yeah that nature is of a subject
to change anything you about to do an
account of the body anything you've done
anyone anything you're doing when I come
to your body being here can that be
otherwise cannot share a different
nature no can they partake in a
different nature can be taken in greater
independence then the basis that's
necessary for its independence so the
only way to maintain that picture is to
keep investing effort to maintain it
effort to ignore what is the necessary
basis for my whole existence inherently
subjected to and what helps you ignoring
is sensual desire anger distraction
acting all these three things engaging
with things they were kind of occupy
your mind so you don't think about so
you don't start feeling this this threat
of the nature of change why do you think
that people start feeling anxious after
then you're bored and for a while when
they don't give in to any any
distraction and sensuality they're left
alone locked himself up just first are
getting bored but in their boredom you
start to become serious that's that's
that's getting serious you you're not
looking at a computer you're not
watching TV you're not reading books
you're just sitting with yourself you
feel like you're beginning to drown in
anxiety and so on what do you think that
is because the entire existence is just
to keep you floating away from admitting
that because naturally if you then start
just being with yourself and no
investing effort in maintenance of this
distraction that helps we know you're
gonna start to feel dukkha on account of
being completely in after non control of
your own sense of control or any sense
of control you can do is completely
secondary completely within completely
enclosed by non control so it's it's
it's almost like a recognition that
while you're alive you recognize you're
actually buried alive how would that
feel you're still alive what's the
problem what's the problem you have air
to breathe the coffin but it's like six
kilometers radius over all around you
and you're so deep yeah means you can't
get out so how would that feel and why
why would you feel awful some directly
threatening isn't no still alive because
it's to breed
what's this shouldn't because you're
still wanting stop control which feels
like it's been taken away from you so if
you basically still as human control
yeah this is the fear that the drag you
would feel in such situation would be
the directly corresponding to the
discrepancy you created with your own
assumption or the assumption being
external to this coffin and so imagine
now when actually that is the reality
you are as the Buddha said the four
mountains are squeezing us and it's
inconceivable that you can you know go
over them or avoid them motivate them
yeah you gonna get crushed like
literally you will already man the
inside of that at the point where you
won't be because of it it's a basic
about first that's first so you are
actually here
your existence anyone's existence it's
closer to being completely in a coffin
as in you cannot conceive the outside of
this body the outside of this senses the
outside of these thoughts so to speak
yet Here I am
maintaining an ocean master controller
in regard to them they obey me I want
this other one that I choose this
achieved s so that is the starting point
but if you realize then so it's not
about denying your control I had no
control over myself
no he's just putting in the perspective
perspective being that no amount of your
control no amount of your possessions no
amount of your ownership no amount of
your satisfaction through sensuality can
ever put you outside of the senses
outside of the given body outside of the
coffin basically you're buried in yeah
well you think the Buddha said it's like
the the existence is are constantly
being like a cow being flayed cow being
eaten by insects from any direction is
absolutely no no murder you can rest
whether it's its thang war so that's a
you can still do all this you can move
around you can turn around in your
coffin yeah you can breathe you can
think you can sing you can do what you
like in a coffin
yeah and often actually people exist and
not that different things you do is just
scratch an immediate edge eat when I'm
bored sleep when I want to sleep
distract myself although you can be in a
coffin why is one frightening one isn't
why is one front wise one person
frightened is another no why is a wonder
cognition frightening the other one
isn't like if you recognize if you think
that you are enclosed first that is
frightening but if you don't take that
first that's not frightening all do you
go about doing the same time say a thing
could you ignore it no but why is it
frightening why is it frightening to
take that being in a coffin first
because it's because that undermines
your assumption that you want to control
and why is that assumption then there
then you are in control
what could use this yeah beginningless
but completely completely utterly
so guess why is that to avoid the pain
yeah yeah sure he has its reasons but
the thing is the only reason it
can be their easiest because you keep
maintaining it through ignoring the fact
that you are in the coffin that's it and
once you real once you understand that
this is the necessary order well also
puts in perspective when people remember
in the suitors when they hear the Buddha
and they get a glimpse of what he's
actually saying and they freak out they
fall on the ground
yeah overwhelmed by anxiety such
screaming where they will kill me that
will crush me don't destroy me I am
buried alive while I'm alive as in my
life is my burial
basically yeah I cannot I'm sobriety
greatest fear is here right now
yeah oh they will kill us they will
destroy the Omegas yeah exactly be at it
because you get you to assume the
external of this which within which
you're full and closed of your senses of
your body how can you know external of
your body right now while we speak your
body is your coffin basically yeah and
again that's what with the certain
different words the entire universe is
within this body
how can you conceive outside of my body
how is that even imaginable well you can
imagine it because that imagination
requires you to ignore the truth yeah
but then that's innovations that stuff
is a thought which is but even that
thought yet cannot really take outside
you can just again where do you realize
or not you are in the coffin yes that's
the thing so the only reason you
experience fear on account of it is
because you still refuse to give up
these ridiculous gratuitous views yeah
that's why you suffer not because you're
in the coffin you always been in the
coffin always fully enclosed within this
body and you are subjected to whatever
that body gets subjected to it's
inconceivable for you to to avoid not
partaking that name yet to avoid that so
basically except the he well what do you
like it or no
Coffee yeah the unis secondary to the
enclosure that your body provides and
whenever you think outside of this body
but you although this is Renault you can
think but make sure that that thought
does not imply as an actual outside of
the body because such thing is
inconceivable so you will stop consume
misconceiving in there you will stop
conceiving it
that's a rudiment it's but misconceiving
i get the matter you provide the footing
for the matter so mindfulness of the
body recognizing your body as the
Sankara for whatever is I'm thinking and
you're building this source of outside
this body yeah that's how you again stop
going so any thoughts about outside of
the body is within the experience of
this body when I think outside that's
already internal yeah and that's exactly
for somebody who's fully developed at
purified from all ignoring the Buddha
said for another hand what is left is
naming form
externally that he can observe the
container yeah less conscious body the
container and then within that container
yeah there are things that are external
external and they're things are slightly
past externalizing things that pertain
to this body and things that pertain to
thought about it but it's all within
this this conscious body as a basis yeah
and when this conscious body breaks
apart for a neuron that's Nirvana there
is no more reappearing with no more
being well again it's not something you
get to read contain you always remain in
the same container of the five
aggregates that's the nature of rebirth
yeah okay just remaining in the same
container with different functional
arrangement within the containment but
it's still the same container that's why
you remember one a lot of times five
hundred lifetimes the Buddha said only
remembering is these five agree to these
five aggregates that you can see now
again it's like they know outside - it
doesn't matter how many eons have spent
how many rivers you've been through no
inconceivable you if you think outside
that thought conceives outside in regard
to inside and everything so everything
that everything inside is of the nature
of
of change yes because why because the
container that you cannot get under
repossess step outside a void is fully
subject to change
let's encounters the container that
determines your life the possibilities
in your life the choices you make you
made you're about to make all of that
that container is not in your control
yeah after Lee after Lincoln silver and
you thinking outside can only be done on
the basis of being enclosed within this
and then you project how there must be
outside but yeah you can never actually
step outside and the sooner you stop
expecting that the sooner you stop
practicing the Dharma correctly because
the way out is not digging the tunnel
out because there is no out how can you
dig a tunnel out of your own body
inconceivable the way out is not being
bothered emotionally not resisting the
discomfort of that which is subjected to
change so the way out is to understand
look I mean how many times we all read
that can you say it's the wire is to
stop wanting to get I um yes if wanted
to get out means craving against what's
currently felt here unpleasantly so it's
good that you want to get out what it's
not good is the way you choose to go
about it I think there is an ignorant
way and there's another I wanted to get
out is where the Buddha meant craving is
to be abandoned when the means of
craving it's just not about like it's
not about getting out but it's just
about not know being more than it's like
say studying and how they are editor
natively how can you also develop that after not
how can you also develop that after not
being bothered by whether you live or
die yeah equanimity mindfulness of death why
yeah equanimity mindfulness of death why
do you think he was so potent did it
buddy said like you know very quickly
your resulting complete this passion or
a bit of madness is worth depending on
whether you were ready not because there
is the nature of things
you are fully enclosed within that
within that within that they were
subjected to to disappear which is what
that is yeah so then everything you do
in your life unless it's dealing with
that is distracting you from it yeah
it's just automatic even if you don't be
distracted if you're doing something on
the basis of ignoring these nature's of
these things necessary for my action to
begin with that's how you maintain you
don't even even if you don't want to
because again can you be building a
family pursuing a job career being a
monk any of it even up to life and if
your life is to be taken away from me do
you have any saying that Kevin same you
can only relatively protect it but even
that you realize like even the threats
that you subjected to you can't even
fathom that so you only have these
projected ideas of threats which means a
projected idea of defending these
threats and that's all it is so far
removed from what you're actually
constantly even while you are defending
yourself subjected to can you tell you
hard hard to beat when to stop to beat
faster yet can you remain alive if that
muscle unit just stops beating so all
you need to do is not forget that
whenever you're about to do something
whenever you're about to make a choice
what's that going to result in is you
will not be able to act out of passion a
version and design for distraction
because again distraction active
distraction is within the container now
that you are not ignoring can you
distract yourself if you were not there
alive to begin with inconceivable so
even your means of escape relative
escape are fully and closer you're not
escape you cannot escape in and that's
why those people freaked out when they
understood oh inescapable their will they will for
oh inescapable their will they will for
sure guaranteed kill me destroy me
because I cannot conceive outside of
this yet I've been going around as if I
am outside and that's where the nature
is so the reason why if kind of don't
want to use permanent permanent is
because permanently permanent is on the
level of people's perceptions oh look
that's impermanent that's no it's on the
level of the nature of things once
people understand that then yeah you can
translate whatever you want but it
he must have that personal connotation
that undermining your sense of ownership
and that's rather than Salveson Cardoni
mm got a good sob Adama another that's
all things that I can engage with take
leave won't know what all things cannot
be mine cannot be my own self because
they're undermined by by the container
that I cannot even conceive controlling
because that's what I think my wonder
like okay so you're not mindful of the
body did subject you these things it's
kind of the extent of it is
inconceivable to you which means you're
always second that you're always
enclosed within it what do I do next now
what you do next is whatever you're
about to do make sure it doesn't
distract you from what you already know
that's what that's why sense restraint
it's basically although you don't know
sense restrain restraining from
sensuality restraining from acting out
of anger and so on it's basically
emulating the right behavior now of
course just by emulating AI behavior
will not necessarily arrive at
understanding but without having been
emulating it rightly you certainly have
no grounds for understanding so it's
kind of learning how to and learning how
to basically Retailer your life so there
are no underlying gratuitous assumption
of the outs external sense of control
mastery ownership who I don't partake in
this yeah we all die but basically you
don't feel yourself you die
so how did the Buddha sum up the
retailer ring of your life they would
then remove these assumptions of
external world outside of this coffin
and also remove any resistance to being
in this coffin of this body because you
choose to get upset an account of it
because you choose to not give up those
creatures external assumptions how did
the Buddha sum up that entire fire is
different why is there no blaze a path
no belief a path means there will be
nothing left unaddressed but it all it's
all rooted in the same context in the
one understanding that's why the right
view comes first the right view
determines the whole no belief or path
is the right path right you drive you
being view free from whatever de nada
being assuming the external sense of
self in regard to the experience as a
whole
something outside of this experience
yeah something else I need a coffin yep
and again you don't need to take off
your ho that's a wrong thought there's
no such thing as a wrong thought it's
only wrong action on a kind of thought
so the thought the thought is the
external okay
allow it to endure yeah so the external
to this experience as a whole can even
designate that for myself gonna think
about it can I have the vaguest notion
of that external dimension in regard to
my experience as a whole if this
experience is a whole he's not there
first yeah so any notion of external
that I have now and I'm allowing to do
is always within this experience that
whole is always step beneath yeah
doesn't matter how far external I go and
that's what doesn't matter how far you
travel in this you knows you'll never
reach the end it's always gonna be step
ahead of it yeah or step beneath you
whichever direction you want you want
the end of the universe
you know you won't reach by traveling
you reach it by giving up that necessary
basis for any direction you can take
necessary basis of attachment to the
body on the ship of the body not seeing
the on each of the body not seeing the
body is Sankara not understanding cigar
saying as in control if you want to stop
assuming the external yet to start
seeing it against the peripheral content
context of internal not by denying oh I
shouldn't be thinking this you are it
that's what October is that's what you
are by internal you mean like body exact
by that container so da so the notion of
external you want to recognize don't try
to get rid of it and certainly don't act
out of it yeah and you will be acting
out of it whenever you act out of desire
yeah ill will or that's why those things
are wrong cuz they perpetuate the
gratuitous parasitic wrong assumption
yeah that's it
so you don't act out of it but you don't
try to deny that you're allowed to do so
there is a genuine sense of I am
external to this I am independent of
this so then take the sense of
Independence yeah I'm independent to things that
yeah I'm independent to things that
happen to me I can choose I can move
left that you move right I can do this
so how would that sense of Independence
then be described while it's there so
you're not denying it it has something
that has arisen thanks to the fact that
there is this body here in the first
place exactly so can you then have any sense
exactly so can you then have any sense
of Independence without this body so is
it an OK to look for the experience as a
whole anywhere else except on the basis
of this body can you conceive any
experience except that's why that's why
I think personally excellence notion of
experience as a whole for me all the
feeling they kind of see into you that's
why I keep keep sort of going back to
the mood as you know the gender of the
container basically if you go out of the
nude there's nothing to copy anything
there's not sighs Michelle Park she's
not sorry you are in that mood yeah and
everything is revealed
you can eyes you can hope when the mood
changes it's gonna be like this universe
but all that is envelope is placed on
that note even the slightest hope yeah
the slightest conceiving is then seen
fully against within this context it's
contained yeah yeah and that's how I
stopped miss concealing trans that's the
thing but yeah but well no you know that
try to know exactly face so traps always
implies I want to get out and always
implies like yeah you were out before
yeah it's just simply you cannot select
these things you're living within the
trap yeah yeah but you don't necessarily need
yeah yeah but you don't necessarily need
to be trapped yes you get trapped when
you choose to ignore that's how you are
trapped by the track you have to live in
is the simile of the herd the suit yeah
the bait right yeah I mean is it like
could you say also just not fighting
they're kind of nature things in a way
yes but see people can do that he takes
the fighting
oh just accept everything just be here
now why that it's important where it's
rooted not like okay it's a bottom what
you do of course what you do well what
are you doing whether there will be
helpful or unhelpful skill for
unskillful is whether it's rooted in you
acting out craving or not whether you're
trying to get rid of things that
displease you or not so truly you can
say you will stop being trapped you stop
being bothered by living in the trap you
will not you will be unable to be
careless in regard to trap if you remove
craving in regard 2010 during mood
trying to get trying to change the
unpleasant mood trying to change
pleasant mood for more pleasant mood
trying to change our present mood for
less unpleasant mood and trying to
change the neutral mood for anything to
feel just not nothing you know that's
too frightening just just give me some
form of distraction or excited and
whatever what are you so so so craving
is the origin of suffering hmm the most
direct description is basically this
sort of underlying wanting these things
which are the needs to change to change
silligan understood
it's a craving yep is wanting these
things which are the nature to change to
change you want these things to change
because because there's you general
change you've already been affected by
change there change you've been bothered
by their nature do you know the do you
so that's where you accept an itch yeah
and then by accepting their nature which
is to change you stop one thing let's
change because that doesn't make any
sense yeah but that's pretty much the
root of every motivation in another mind
would do which is once you something to
change yeah that your action is in fact
that is action isn't it action is won't
see things to change
exist oh yes
good action or bad action yeah and why
do you want things to change because
they've changed because they've changed
because the change in a way that I don't
like which is always yeah see when they
change for better you one more yeah
that's right when they change for walls
you one less either way you want on
account of change and what is it what is
it that you could possibly want
oh that's another change yeah so because
of the change I suffer and in return to
free myself from suffering I run back
straight into the change here that's a
definition of a bait you get hooked
because you're hooked you can hook even
harder because you just fool you're
full-on like resisting everything
rejecting it and each time you do that
the hook gets deeper and deeper there
you said the only way to release
yourself from the hook is to stop
resisting the things on that peripheral
level on the level of Sankara on the
level of determinations on that level of
giving where you recognize that you have
no control or recognizing that this or
on the level of the nature as I would
say what can we say no much no matter
how much I resist this hmm
I'm doing
that is fully enclosed within this
shovel by developing discretion in
regard to your own craving yeah
realizing that doesn't matter if I go if
I don't if I say yes if I say no doesn't
make any difference cannot step outside
of it
thus you regain the perspective yeah
outside of what outside of this thing
that I'm attending right here right now
yeah I stopped assuming the genuine stop
conceiving the genuine existence of the
outside of this which cannot be known on
the basis of this inside one most
practical level you cannot experience
anything outside of your body engaging
with things on account of whatever your
desires it's your body didn't engages
with it and your thought of the world
outside of your body is a thought that's
within this body now reset it's a wrong
thought well it's a wrong thought if it
misconceives the right order but
otherwise it's just the thought of
outside which I now know is fully within
this body so when you are gripping
something with your hand what is your
experience there are you actually
accessing the matter of this thing you
are touching oh you just have the
experience of your body touching
something see even notion of something applies a
see even notion of something applies a
certain external how can you even know
that without this basis of the body so
that doesn't mean everything is in my
mind means everything is within the
relationship of body and the mind says
like it's funny like even like in the
suits as it says like the time sights
and sounds that kind of you can think I
said this the body over here and then
there's those things that are separate
yeah yeah but again the suitors don't
actually say that no but what like me
because people's views the end up having
that conclusion the suitors say sights
eyes and sites and then consciousness
they come together yep so eyes inside
said on one level yeah share the same
level it's not eyes in here sights on
the other level
ize insights and corresponding
consciousness comes and that's why one
is pressure by sites so sites are the
level of your eyes eyes are on the level
of the sites and usually because of the
wrong view that people assume eyes are
in me sights are outside another
assumption of outside you have to
reverse it so you find that sites are
within the eyes that are in you how can
you know sites
how can you imagine sites how can you
even even even fantasize about sites if
they've never an Amish head harness
inconceivable inconceivable yet here you
are thinking you can access all these
sites independent of your eyes any
having any thing that you could imagine
visible requires the necessary basis on
the audit that's what the Buddha said
the entire universe literally you travel
to different cosmos where it's still
within the body and cannot step outside
of this body and it can only be in those
six domains oh yeah of course yeah
that's if you want to look at the
aspects of that one unit of the body is
one unit one base of the six senses in
here so then the thought of outside is
now seen against the backdrop of fully
enclosed within this body
and when you start singular that there
will be no more basis for a notion of I
am outside independent of this
experience as a whole means there will
be no more out of other and yeah so I
was just thinking about that
but our body is Alisha it's like him
it's just I've been subjected to you
subjected to that which is abrupt in
uncontrollable like you can't repossess
it from its roots you can tell it to be
like this and not age or not die and you
just can't English you so just don't
forget that as the ultimate context
whenever you're about to act speak or
think and whenever you are acting
speaking and thinking it's not like that
you're denying that it's just including
that within that broader context it
exact that'll mean you think against
this backdrop means the context remains
this part of your actions and your
thoughts so as you keep saying it's
about establishing your context
cause that's what the review is the
right context a right context and you
until they tell you until that context
is unshakable because nothing can't not
be included in it
exactly and that context is unshakable
is when you yourself stop shaking it
through your carelessness he was always
unshakable that's what I said our
consciousness was always pure you can
really corrupt things only ignoring that
not knowing that through your ignorance
that's what corruption is there
[Music]
so whether it's the mood whether it's
the body literally it's a presently
enduring context in regards to anything
including right this right now oh yes so
like next time I think about the outside
order these thoughts are we gonna
present enduring mood yeah can imagine
outside of that mood
I can imagine before or after I can
imagine moving within it can imagine
outside of us can imagine me being first
mood being second inconceivable think
about it the more you think about it
they're clearly to become the the more
the more significant that context would
be the more easily accessible that
context would be here which means the
the the better mindfulness of it will be
established to the mind is well said in
that said Madonna or he develops
mindfulness to the extent necessary well
he develops context to the extent
necessary for final knowledge as in for
the knowledge that cannot divert the
order with gratuitous assumption anymore
take second to be the first and first to
be the second take outside to be the
inside and inside to be outside
inconceivable because you develop the
context they've been including everything
they've been including everything
sufficient amount of time any thought
any movement what if any doubt that's
again free from a tabata means free from
doubt because you can doubt the content
you can't doubt the night present nature
of enduring doubt so the content of the
doubt work work work
it's because the nail is a doubt
enduring there so the doubt cannot take
outside doesn't matter how much you
think so that's all mean instead of
focusing and clarifying the content of
your doubt yeah just focus on including
its nature within the necessary basis of
the five agree we didn't necessary so
presently during mood within the
necessary basis of presently given body
there so now ignoring the context that
has manifested yeah so then you're
perfectly capable of enduring doubt and
not suffering on account of it and
certainly not falling back to the wrong
view wrong view means wrong assumption
wrong assumption means perverted order